[
    {
        "question": "What country was called Northern Rhodesia until 1984?",
        "answer": "Zambia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city is named for a Roman general famed for leaving his troops and retiring to his farm?",
        "answer": "Cincinnati"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Ecuador?",
        "answer": "Andean condor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Angola?",
        "answer": "Red-crested turaco"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Finland?",
        "answer": "Whooper swan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Greece?",
        "answer": "Little owl"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Honduras?",
        "answer": "Scarlet macaw"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iceland?",
        "answer": "Gyrfalcon"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US territory includes the islands of Saint Croix, Saint John and Saint Thomas?",
        "answer": "US Virgin Islands"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Florida?",
        "answer": "Tallahassee"
    },
    {
        "question": "What river flows through Colorado`s Black Canyon?",
        "answer": "Gunnison River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Okeechobee is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "Grand Mesa is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gaborone is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Botswana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gaborone is the capital of which African country?",
        "answer": "Botswana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Botswana is landlocked by which four countries?",
        "answer": "South Africa, Namibia, Zimbabwe, and Zambia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What desert covers most of southern Mongolia?",
        "answer": "The Gobi desert"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the narrow, inland sea, separates the western Asia from northeastern Africa?",
        "answer": "Red sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Lisbon lies on which river?",
        "answer": "Tagus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most common county name in the United States?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long was the Oregon Trail?",
        "answer": "2170 miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sea lies between China and the Korean Peninsula?",
        "answer": "Yellow Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the Inyo Mountains?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the official state animal of Kansas?",
        "answer": "The bison"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the smallest state in the US?",
        "answer": "Rhode Island"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Connecticut?",
        "answer": "Hartford"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Florida`s largest lake?",
        "answer": "Lake Okeechobee"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cape Canaveral is located in which US state?",
        "answer": "Florida"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are Italy`s two largest islands?",
        "answer": "Sicily and Sardinia"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many `emirates` make up the United Arab Emirates?",
        "answer": "Seven"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Cherokee rose is the state flower of which U.S. state?",
        "answer": "Georgia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are Zinfandel grapes from?",
        "answer": "Croatia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the windiest continent?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the only tropical botanical garden listed on UNESCO`s World Heritage Site list?",
        "answer": "Singapore"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the smallest country by square mileage in North America?",
        "answer": "St. Kitts & Nevis"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most visited place in the United States?",
        "answer": "Times Square"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the first Disney theme park outside the U.S. built?",
        "answer": "Tokyo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find a museum dedicated to the history of bread?",
        "answer": "Ulm, Germany"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Nigeria?",
        "answer": "Abuja"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main currency on the island of Oahu?",
        "answer": "US dollar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Trafalgar Cemetery located?",
        "answer": "Gibraltar"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country`s major seaport is Alexandria?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "The underground lake, The Lost Sea, is located in which US state`s Craighead Caverns?",
        "answer": "Tennessee"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Makah Indians lived on which coast?",
        "answer": "West coast"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is the largest in the World?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Peach State`?",
        "answer": "Georgia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Kissimmee River flows into what lake?",
        "answer": "Lake Okeechobee"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the third largest National Park in the US?",
        "answer": "Death Valley National Park"
    },
    {
        "question": "What UK city is served by John Lennon Airport?",
        "answer": "Liverpool"
    },
    {
        "question": "Riyadh is the capital of what Middle-Eastern country?",
        "answer": "Kingdom of Saudi Arabia"
    }
]